

OLUWATOBI OMORUBORE

• DETAILS •

https://tobi-omorubore.dev/ +2348189808987 tobbyzomo221@gmail.com

∘ SKILLS ∘

Java, Kotlin, Dart, Python, JavaScript,
TypeScript, NodeJS, Swift, ReactJS,
HTML, CSS, Markdown

3rd party API integration

Software Architecture (MVVM, MVC, MVP, DDD, Clean, DPs, TDD)

Sport programmer

Version Control System (Git and GitHub)

SQL, No-SQL, firebase, MongoDB, JDBC, Room

Phone Repair

Jira, Kaban, Slack, Scrum, Confluence, Figma

∘ LANGUAGES ∘

English

○ LINKS ○

Collaction app
Travelcrew.app

SimpleButton Mockup

Pet Selection App

MHG app

Github Portfolio

Twitter

LinkedIn

Medium

PROFILE

A software engineer experienced in building mobile and web apps using Flutter, Python, Java, Kotlin, Swift and Web frameworks (ReactJS).

I have a good knowledge of software development lifecycles. I am able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate as part of a p team.

The LINKS section has clickable links to my portfolio. Or see my-portfolio-website.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Software Engineer (2022 - present)

With Collaction (A start-up in the Netherlands) on part-time. I help with:

- Building their mobile app using Flutter. Website URL is: Collaction.org
- Tools/Skills: Bloc, Domain-Driven Design (DDD). Backend using Next-JS. ReactJs

Software Engineer (Jun2023 - Nov2023)

With ZinoxTech on Full-time. Site URL. I help build:

- An Image Transformer: URL, real-time image manipulation. Similar to imagekit.io
- Logistics Aggregator: between multiple couriers to transport items. With consideration for partners with intercepting polygons.
- Headless Image Micro-Service: Rest and GraghQL endpoints, that a client can integrate to fetch image from multiple sources.
- Tools/Skills: Python, FastApi, AWS S3, MongoDB, MySQL, Postman-doc.

Data Scientist (3 months. Feb – May 2023)

<u>For a client</u> (Given a dry bean dataset, develop a system for automatic detection of 7 types of dry bean seeds.

 K-Nearest Neighbour (KNN) and Support Vector Machine (SVM) was used for the analysis. With performance measured. View solution

Contract Mobile App Work (2020 -2022)

With MostHighGrade a start-up located in the United States of America:

 MHG app solution for showcasing smoking related products. Worked with owner from the Idea stage, app requirement analysis, to mock-up design, Implementation. Launched app on Apple Test flight.

<u>With the Button Simple team</u>: Built SIMPLE BUTTON an app that allows Care givers to communicate with their aged parents.

Software Engineer (2020 -2021)

<u>With TravelCrew</u> (a mobile app for friends to share and organize travel plans and even create full itineraries together). I help with:

- Building their mobile app using flutter. Website URL is: travelcrew.app
- Tools/Skills: Dart, Bloc, Firebase

Freelance Mobile App Developer on Fiverr (2019 - 2021)

On Fiverr, I offer the following freelancing service:

 App development, UI/UX design, custom app design and implementation of complex UIs with Flutter or Java/Kotlin Android. Depending on client's request.

Open-Source Contributor on GitHub (2018 -2020)

- TEST for SEED DECK on GitHub. A simple app for gardeners to track their seeds in the garden and see how different varieties perform
- Contribute to STACKED: A flutter package for state management

Medical Researcher/Pharmacy and Lab Survey

2017 (March to May)

- Worked with a medical doctor as his research assistant. The hospital gathered data on medical laboratories and pharmacies in Lagos State.
- My job was to visit the various branches of the laboratory and pharmacy in Lagos. I interviewed patients and have my survey book filled. 8 laboratories and 12 pharmacies in total, across 8 Local Government Areas.

IT Support - System troubleshooting - Phone Repair Engineer (2015 - 2019)

- During my time working as Oracle and Google Campus Ambassador. I fix trainees computer issues. OS repair, file recovery, fix system crashes, Virus detection.
- 2015 2019 work as a phone repair engineer at Computer village Ikeja.

Mobile App Developer at LAUTECH (2019)

For my final year project, I research 'The digital data & privacy of the deceased'. For my submission, I built a Digital will app called JUST-WILL, which allows a person to decide what happens to their data after being dead or inactive. Tools/Skills: Java, Android, XML, Android studio.

Oracle Java Campus Ambassador at Oracle, Ogbomoso

2017 - 2019

- I served as Oracle's Java campus ambassador for my University (LAUTECH)
- I pioneered several tech training and hackathons that promote Java.
- One is LOCAL HACK DAY 2018. An event which attracted over 450 attendees & featured tech solutions. The program was planned and executed within 10 days. See the <u>Medium post</u> I wrote about the event.

Competitive/Sport Programmer. (2015 - 2018)

I engage in available code competitions. Such as:

• HashCode, Summer of Code, GeeksForGeeks, Hactoberfest. HackerRank, LeetCode and CodeSignal questions.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Ladoke Akintola University of Technology, Ogbomoso, Oyo state

2014 — 2019

COURSES

Android Certification Training Course, Edureka

July 2020 — November 2020

¶ REFERENCES

References available upon request